Lucas Rosinelli da Rocha

Lisbon, Portugal

+351 965 507 579 | contact@lucasrosinelli.com | LinkedIn

Career Summary

Experienced Software Developer with solutions created focused on company needs. Have consistently maintained products, adding new features and improving their scalability and efficiency. A team member which keeps in mind that excellent interpersonal relationship is important as a high-quality product meeting deadline.

Work Experience

2019 - Present Lisbon, Portugal 2012 - 2019São Paulo/SP. Brazil

Software Engineer | Vision-Box

Full Stack Developer | Nexxys

- Improvements, performance, and refactoring implemented, focusing on coding readability and maintenance, scalability, and reusability
- Innovative by offering eight years of experience in the full software development lifecycle - from concept through delivery of next-generation applications and customizable solutions
- 85-90% of products are created using Visual Studio 2015/2017, C# (3.5 and 4.6) and ASP.NET MVC, Web API – all of them are supported by SQL Server and MongoDB databases - version controller: Git
- Increased the company's revenue by introducing a new idea in the real-time data delivery solution for our clients

2006 - 2012 São Paulo/SP. Brazil

Software Developer | DigiSystem

- Analyzed user requirements, and translated client needs into application design
- Reduced project costs by focusing on double-check requirements and create more accurate test processes with code review
- Design, code, and support software solutions that can easily be scaled depending on client needs

2004 - 2006

Programmer | Politec

Taquaritinga/SP, **Brazil**

- Wrote code to specification in order to build two government-facing web-based applications
- Maintain product quality by carrying out reviews, performing continual tests, and analyzing feedback

Education

2008 - 2012São Paulo/SP, Universidade Presbiteriana Mackenzie

Brazil

B.S. Computer Science

Training

Dec 2015

Apr 2016 ASP.NET MVC 5 Enterprise Applications (24 hours) - Eduardo Pires (Microsoft MVP Visual Studio and Development Technologies)

Rich Domains with Domain-Driven Design, SOLID, SPA and Unit Tests (24 hours) -

André Baltieri (Microsoft MVP ASP.NET/IIS)

Nov 2013 20480 - Programming in HTML5 and JavaScript and CSS3 (40 hours) - Ka Solution

Additional Skills & Interest

- Expert knowledge of .NET environment such as C#, ASP.NET (MVC, Web Forms, Web Services, Web API, WCF, SignalR), Windows Forms, Windows Services, LINQ and Entity Framework
- Proficient in SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB and Oracle databases

- Intermediate knowledge of Ionic, React Native, TypeScript, Xcode, DDD, NodeJS and microservices
- Proficient in Web environment development: HTML5, CSS3, XML, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS, AJAX, JSON, REST and SOAP
- Extensive experience with design patterns (GoF), OOD, UML, unit testing, SOLID, teamwork, problem-solving and creative thinking